Guide to the Alaska Commercial Company Records, 1868-1940 JL006
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Series 1. General Accounts: Papers, 1888 - 1940
  - Subseries C. Financial Reports from Unalaska, 1936 - 1940
    - Financial statements, 1893 - 1897 (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Financial statements, 1898 (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Financial statements, 1899 (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Financial statements, 1900 (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Financial statements, 1901 (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - Financial statements [1 of 2], 1902 (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - Financial statements [2 of 2], 1902 (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - Financial statements, 1903 (Box 15, Folder 12)
    - Financial statements, 1904 (Box 15, Folder 13)
    - Financial statements, 1905 (Box 15, Folder 14)
    - Financial statements, 1906 (Box 15, Folder 15)
    - Financial statements, 1907 (Box 15, Folder 16)
    - Northern Commercial Co. bylaws, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 17)
    - Cash book, 1936 Sept. - 1936 Dec. (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - Cash book, 1937 Jan. - 1937 June (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - Cash book, 1937 June - 1937 Sept. (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Cash book, 1937 Oct. - 1938 Mar. (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - Cash book, 1938 Apr. - 1938 July (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Cash book, 1938 Aug. - 1938 Dec. (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Cash book, 1939 Jan. - 1939 Mar. (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - Cash book, 1939 Apr. - 1939 July (Box 19.1, Folder 1)
    - Cash book, 1939 Aug. - 1939 Nov. (Box 19.1, Folder 2)
    - Cash book, 1939 Dec. - 1940 Apr. (Box 19.1, Folder 3)
    - Cash book, 1940 May - 1940 July (Box 19.1, Folder 4)
    - Cash book, 1940 Aug. - 1940 Sept. (Box 19.1, Folder 5)
- Series 2. General Accounts: Ledgers, 1868 - 1940
  - Subseries A. Alaska Commercial Co., 1868 - 1940
    - Certificates of stock, 1868-1914 (Box 20)
    - Dividend book, 1872-1892 (Box 21)
    - Transfer journal, 1870-1918 (Box 22)
    - Stock ledger, 1870-1917 (Box 23)
    - Ledger, 1873-1896 (Box 24)
    - Ledger, 1896-1899 (Box 25)
    - Ledger, 1900-1903 (Box 26)
    - Ledger, 1904-1907 (Box 27)
    - Ledger, 1908-1911 (Box 28)
    - Ledger, 1912-1915 (Box 29)
    - Ledger, 1916-1918 (Box 30)
    - Ledger, 1919-1922 (Box 31)
    - Ledger, 1923-1926 (Box 32)
    - Ledger, 1927-1929 (Box 33)
    - Ledger, 1930-1934 (Box 34)
    - Ledger, 1935-1937 (Box 35)
    - Petty ledger, 1910-1922 (Box 36)
    - Cash book, 1924-1927 (Box 37)
    - Cash book, 1927-1931 (Box 38)
    - Cash book, 1931-1933 (Box 39)
    - Cash book, 1933-1935 (Box 40)
    - Cash book, 1935-1937 (Box 41)
    - Cash book, 1937-1940 (Box 42)
    - Draft book, 1901-1917 (Box 43)
    - Credit sales trial balance, 1937-1938 (Box 44)
    - Dawson ledger, 1901 (Box 45)
    - Dawson ledger, 1904-1912 (Box 46)
    - Yukon Saw Mill ledger, 1908-1915 (Box 47)
    - Fur book, 1871-1904 (Box 48)
    - Fur average record, 1868-1936 (Box 49)
  - Subseries B. Northern Commercial Co., 1906 - 1926
    - Minutes, 1906 - 1926 (Box 50)
      - Minutes, 1906-1912
      - Minutes, 1913-1916
      - Minutes, 1921-1926
    - Stock journal, 1906 - 1921 (Box 51)
      - Stock certificates: common, 1906-1922
      - Stock certificates: preferred, 1906-1921
      - Stock journal and ledger: common, 1906-1926
      - Stock journal and ledger: preferred, 1906-1921
    - Private ledger, 1922-1925 (Box 52)
    - Private Home Office General Ledger, 1906-1922 (Box 53)
    - Private journal, 1914-1920 (Box 54)
    - Private journal, 1920-1926 (Box 55)
    - Journal, 1926 - [?] (Box 56)
    - Cash book, 1922-1926 (Box 57)
    - Trial balance (private ledger), 1920-1926 (Box 58)
  - Subseries C. Northern Navigation Co., 1905 - 1921
    - Minutes, 1906 - 1921 (Box 59)
      - Minutes, 1906-1912
      - Minutes, 1913-1916
      - Minutes, 1917-1921
    - Stock Journal, 1906 - 1921 (Box 60)
      - Stock certificates: common, 1906-1921
      - Stock certificates: preferred, 1905-1917
      - Stock journal and ledger: common, 1906-1921
      - Stock journal and ledger: preferred, 1906-1918
      - Yukon Express Co.- minutes re: incorporation
    - Private Home Office General Ledger, 1906-1921 (Box 61)